Md Zishan Akhtar

QA ENGINEER

Profile

QA Engineer with 3.5 years of experience of writing manual test cases and automated test scripts using Selenium, Appium, Rest Assured and TestNG framework. Train new testers, review work and optimize processes. Work alongside developers to uncover and resolve problems in advance of releases.

Selenium with java: 3.5 Years

Appium with java: 3.5 Years

API Testing with Postman: 3.5 Years

Manual database testing with SQL queries: 3.5 Years

API Automation using Rest Assured: 1 Year

Database automation testing with JDBC: 1 Year

Employment History

QA Engineer, Phasorz Technologies Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

OCTOBER 2019 - MAY 2021

- Automation testing of android application using Appium Java TestNG framework.
- Running automated test script for android application on real android devices, android emulators and AWS Device Farm.
- Automation testing of Web Application using Selenium Java TestNG framework.
- Collaborated with developers and product managers for discussion on features.
- · Wrote test cases for the features on TestRail.
- · Integration testing after merging the features.
- · Regression testing before the app release.
- · Bug reporting and tracking on Jira.
- · Wrote SQL queries to test database.
- · Provided KT to new joiners.

QA Engineer, Bewakoof Brands Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

MAY 2021 - MARCH 2022

- Automation testing of Web Application using Selenium Java TestNG framework.
- Collaborated with developers and product managers for discussion on features.
- · Wrote test cases for the features.
- · Manual testing of features.
- · Identifying and reporting bugs.
- · Bug reporting and tracking on Jira.
- · Wrote SQL queries to test database.

QA Engineer, Homevista Decor And Furnishings Pvt Ltd, Bengaluru

APRIL 2022 - MARCH 2023

 Automation testing of Web Application using Selenium - Java - TestNG framework.

Details

Alamganj Patna, 800007 7064025470 zishanakhtar56@gmail.com

Skills

Java

Selenium

Appium

Automated Testing

API Testing

Rest Assured

SOL

Manual Testing

Hobbies

Singing, playing piano Photo & Video editing

- Automation testing of android app using Appium Java TestNG framework on real android devices as well as on android emulators.
- · Automation testing of APIs using Rest Assured.
- Automation testing of databases using JDBC to verify data mismatch among multiple databases.
- Collaborated with developers and product managers for discussion on features and script requirements.
- · Wrote test cases for the features.
- · Manual testing of features.
- · Bug reporting and tracking on Jira.

Education

Secondary School, Ishan International Public School, Patna

APRIL 2011 - MARCH 2012

Higher Secondary, Ishan International Public School, Patna

APRIL 2012 - MARCH 2014

B. Tech in Mechanical Engineering, Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology, Bhubaneshwar

JULY 2015 - MAY 2019